我在纳粹德国这堆陈年旧事里刨了几十年了
I've spent decades investigating Nazi Germany and its leaders,
但凡对这题材稍有涉猎的人
and anyone who has spent any time on this subject
都免不了会挖到点他们高级将领的私生活猛料
inevitably will learn things about the private lives of such men.
这些猛料嘛，好多都已经是公开的秘密了
Much is, of course, well known,
从希特勒的女友和那奇特的性癖好
from Adolf Hitler's girlfriends and strange attitudes to sex,
到戈培尔博士那堪比发情期山羊的私生活
to Dr. Goebbels' behavior that had more in common with a rutting goat,
这家伙仗着位高权重，睡遍了一票女明星和女演员
a man who happily abused his powerful position to bed a series of starlets and actresses,
一面扮演着顾家好男人
despite playing the happily married family man,
一面又让希姆莱搞出了婚外情和私生子，真是令人大开眼界
to Heinrich Himmler and his unlikely affair and secret love children.
这么说吧，纳粹高层们在德国公众面前树立的光辉形象
Let's just say the public image Nazi leaders projected to an adoring German public
跟他们私底下的德行和癖好，那真是差了十万八千里
was often severely at variance with their private behavior and predilections.
当然了，这种当面一套背后一套的指控可不光是纳粹的专利
But, of course, such an accusation is by no means limited to just Nazis,
历史上任何一群手握大权的男人，无论过去还是现在，都一个德行
but to any group of powerful men throughout history, then and now.
但有位纳粹高层，似乎总能让人看不透他的真相
But one top Nazi leader has seemingly confounded attempts to find his truth,
此人正是赫尔曼·戈林
and that man was Hermann Göring.
迈耶也来辣
在我研究纳粹这么些年里
In my many years of researching Nazis,
关于戈林性取向和本性的流言蜚语我听得耳朵都快起茧了
I've come across the rumors concerning Göring's sexuality and nature enough times
足以让我明白这位帝国元帅的公众形象里，肯定藏着猫腻
to know that something wasn't quite honest in the Reichsmarschall's public image,
有些东西不是被藏起来了，就是被硬生生压下去了
that something was being hidden or perhaps repressed.
不过，我还是很有把握地告诉各位，赫尔曼·戈林不是同性恋
However, I feel confident in stating that Hermann Göring was not gay,
但他很可能有一种被精神分析学家称为“后性实践”的行为
but he most probably did exhibit what psychoanalysts term a post-sexual practice,
至于这具体是啥，我待会儿再跟你们细说
and I will tell you what exactly that was later on.
你想想就能明白，戈林在世的时候
You can understand how, during his own lifetime,
在他那帮同僚圈子里，不知道让多少人惊掉了下巴
Göring raised more than a few eyebrows amongst the circle of men that he worked among.
这哥们是纳粹高层里独一份的精致男孩，不仅天天化妆
He was the only senior Nazi leader who regularly wore makeup,
有时候还敢顶着大浓妆抛头露面
sometimes in public.
戈林对那些亮瞎眼的珠宝
Goering's taste in ostentatious jewelry
和娘里娘气的衣服制服的品味
and often rather effeminate clothing and uniforms
让大家都在背后嘀咕，这位看起来两度婚姻美满的帝国元帅
set tongues wagging that the apparently twice happily married Reichsmarschall
怕不是个深柜，或者至少是个双性恋吧
was a secret homosexual, or at least that he was bisexual.
这些流言蜚语嘛，二战后自然而然地成了流行文化的一部分
Such rumors and gossip have, of course, entered popular culture since World War II,
戈林私下里也常常被描绘成娘娘腔，甚至是异装癖
and Göring has often been portrayed privately as effeminate or, indeed, as a transvestite,
尤其是在1988年的电视电影《住在里兹酒店的男人》里
notably in the television movie from 1988, The Man Who Lived at the Ritz,
由才华横溢的乔斯·阿克兰扮演的戈林简直是入木三分
where Göring was played by the brilliant Joss Ackland.
当时见过他的人，都对他那浮夸的衣着和香水味儿议论纷纷
Contemporary witnesses commented repeatedly on Goering's flamboyant dress scents.
实际上，在纳粹高层内部，这位帝国元帅有时被戏称为“喷香水的尼禄”
In fact, among senior Nazis, the Reichsmarschall was sometimes referred to as the perfumed Nero
就是那个荒淫无度的罗马皇帝
after the dissolute Roman Emperor.
瑞士外交官卡尔·布克哈特，就亲眼目睹过戈林在卡琳堂的家中放松的模样
Swiss diplomat Carl Burckhardt witnessed Göring relaxing at home at Carinhall,
那儿是他在柏林北边巨大的乡间庄园
his huge country estate north of Berlin,
庄园的名字是为了纪念他过世的瑞典第一任妻子
named after his deceased Swedish first wife,
他对亡妻的敬爱和崇拜简直到了痴迷的程度
whom he continued to revere and worship after death,
搞得他第二任妻子，德国女演员埃米·佐内曼，心里很不是滋味
much to the consternation of his second wife, German actress Emmy Zoneman.
布克哈特回忆说，当时戈林斜躺在一张奥斯曼沙发上，裤腿卷到膝盖
Burckhardt recalled Göring reclining on an Ottoman sofa, with his trouser leg rolled up to the knee,
露出了红衣主教般的红色丝袜，浮肿的脸上还挂着一副任性的表情
exposing red silk stockings like a cardinal, with a petulant look on his bloated face,
他的嘴巴塌陷，皱得像个老太太似的
his mouth sunken and puckered like an old woman's.
另一位府上贵客，德国外交官乌尔里希·冯·哈塞尔回忆说
Another houseguest, German diplomat Ulrich von Hassel,
戈林一天能换好几身行头
recalled that Göring would change his outfit several times a day,
经常穿着和服出现在晚宴客人面前
often appearing for dinner in front of guests wearing a kimono,
或者穿着一件罗马式的托加长袍，用一个沉甸甸的金扣子系着
or a Roman-style toga, fastened with a heavy gold clasp,
脚上还踩着一双毛茸茸的卧室拖鞋
and wearing fur-lined bedroom slippers,
手指上戴满了又大又闪的戒指，生怕别人看不见
fingers dripping with huge, ostentatious rings.
说真的，根据目击者的证词来判断
In fact, he appears to have had, judging from witness testimony,
他好像有一大堆稀奇古怪的衣服
a vast array of peculiar outfits,
花里胡哨、招摇过市、耸人听闻，跟他那个军事领袖的形象简直是八竿子打不着
gaudy, ostentatious, sensational, and somewhat removed from his image as a military leader.
我得再强调一遍，穿这些衣服的时候，他脸上还经常抹着粉
I shall add again that make-up was often worn with such outfits,
有人就注意到，有一次戈林参加1943年在柏林举行的年度英雄纪念日阅兵
and indeed it was noted on one occasion that Göring attended the annual Heroes Memorial Day parade in 1943 in Berlin,
他穿着他那身独一无二的淡蓝色帝国元帅制服和军大衣
dressed in his unique powder-blue Reichs-Marshal's uniform and greatcoat,
脚蹬一双鲜红色的皮马靴，脸上还化着妆
wearing bright red leather jackboots and make-up,
镶满珠宝的手指紧紧握着他那根同样镶满珠宝的帝国元帅权杖
his jewel-encrusted fingers gripping his jewel-encrusted Reichs-Marshal's baton.
那场面，绝对震撼我妈一整年
Eyebrows were certainly raised.
贝尼托·墨索里尼的女婿，意大利外交部长齐亚诺伯爵
Benito Mussolini's son-in-law, the Italian foreign minister, Count Ciano,
回忆起1941年与戈林的会面，对他那身打扮评价了一番
recalled meeting Göring in 1941, and commented on his appearance,
说戈林穿着一件毛皮大衣，就像
that Göring was wearing a fur coat, like, quote,
“一个高级妓女去看歌剧时穿的那种”
a high-grade prostitute wears to the opera, end quote.
要想了解戈林的性格，或许可以从他加入纳粹之前的生活里找到些蛛丝马迹
Some clues to Goering's personality may be deduced from his pre-Nazi life.
他爸那边是老柏林正黑旗出身
Born into an upper-class German family on his father's side,
他妈却是工人阶级，而他从小是在他犹太教父的城堡里长大的
but with a working-class mother, he grew up in castles owned by his Jewish godfather,
这位教父，同时也是他妈的情人
who was also his mother's lover.
他是在极尽奢华的环境和一大群仆人的簇拥下长大的
He was raised amongst considerable luxury and a small army of servants,
后来的人生里，他显然是对上流社会的生活上了瘾
and was plainly addicted to higher-class living and later life,
变得那么有钱有势，以至于他能够活得像
becoming so rich and powerful that he was able to live like,
而且确实穿得也像个罗马皇帝，住在一堆豪宅里
and indeed dressed like a Roman emperor, in a collection of beautiful homes,
周围还堆满了数不清的艺术品，有的是买的，有的是抢的
surrounded by vast quantities of both purchased and looted art.
年轻的时候，他身体素质那是杠杠的，胆子也大
He was physically brave, certainly as a younger man.
他那枚蓝马克斯勋章，也就是德意志帝国最高的英勇勋章
His pour Le Mérite, Imperial Germany's highest award for gallantry,
就是最好的证明，他可是一战时期的王牌飞行员
attests to that fact, having served as a World War I fighter pilot
在西线战场上空，干掉了20多架协约国的飞机
who downed over 20 Allied planes in combat over the Western Front.
然而，自从他在慕尼黑的啤酒馆暴动中大腿中枪受伤后
However, following his being shot in the thigh and wounded
就是1921年那次
from the 1921 Bierhul Putsch in Munich,
希特勒和纳粹企图用武力夺权那天
when Hitler and the Nazis had attempted to seize power by force,
他后来在瑞典流亡期间精神崩溃了
he later suffered a nervous breakdown in exile in Sweden,
最后还进了精神病院
and ended up in a mental hospital,
而且有人说，他余生大部分时间都对吗啡上了瘾
and also, some said, addicted to morphine for most of the rest of his life,
尽管这一点后来也受到了一些质疑
although this has been challenged to some degree.
1925年，在他待在瑞典一家精神病院期间
During his time in a Swedish mental institution in 1925,
戈林的医疗报告指出，他情绪极不稳定
his medical report noted that Göring was highly emotional
是个以自我为中心的歇斯底里症患者，还患有迫害妄想症
and a self-centred hysteric, suffering from a persecution complex.
据说他还极度自负，自信心爆棚
He was also said to possess an exaggerated self-confidence.
戈林的一位医生说，他当时已经是个瘾君子了
One of his doctors said that Göring, now a drug addict,
还曾经欺负过他的第一任妻子
who had bullied his first wife,
根本就缺乏最基本的道德勇气
lacked fundamental moral courage.
他性格里的这些毛病，后来因为巨大的权力、名望和金钱
These aspects of his personality were to be considerably magnified
而被无限放大了
by the addition of huge power, fame, and money.
二战期间，跟戈林共事过的人都说
Göring was noted in World War II
他这人又懒又腐败
by those who had to work with him as being lazy, corrupt,
对他手下的空军飞行员和部委工作人员态度粗鲁
brusque with his Luftwaffe pilots and ministerial staff,
但他又能自嘲
but also able to laugh at himself,
这在纳粹那帮头头里可是蝎子粑粑独一份
which was unique amongst Nazi leaders,
而且穿衣服极其浮夸
and hugely flamboyant in dress.
他还有个怪癖，就是痴迷于给自己颁发各种奖章和勋章
His obsession with having himself awarded medals and decorations
这是他性格里另一个奇葩的地方
was another peculiar aspect of his personality.
他永远都不满足
He was never satisfied,
虽然已经拿到了德意志帝国的最高荣誉
and though a holder of Imperial Germany's highest award,
后来又被授予了纳粹德国同等级的最高勋章
and later awarded Nazi Germany's highest equivalents,
骑士十字勋章
the Knight's Cross,
再后来还有铁十字大十字勋章
and later the Grand Cross of the Iron Cross,
后面这个可是专门给他一个人设的独家奖项
the latter a unique award to him only,
但他总想要更多
he always wanted more.
有一次
On one occasion,
他发现自己想给自己弄个意大利什么高级勋章的企图失败了
when he discovered that his attempts to garner for himself some high Italian award had failed,
戈林的反应竟然是哇地一声哭了出来
Göring's response was to burst into tears.
他经常佩戴过量的奖章
He often wore excessive amounts of medals,
或者戴那种特别定制的升级版奖章
or special improved versions of such medals.
举个例子，他的大十字勋章是白金打造的
For example, his Grand Cross was made of platinum,
他还戴着一个镶满钻石的飞行员观察员徽章
and he also wore a diamond-encrusted Pilot Observer badge,
等等等等
and so on,
这下流言就更多了，说他不像个英雄士兵
fuelling rumours that he was rather like a woman
倒像个女人守着自己的首饰盒
with a jewellery box,
宝贝得不得了
rather than heroic soldier.
他胖得走了形，帅气的容貌一去不复返
He bloated up, losing his good looks,
看起来越来越不健康，越来越放荡
looking increasingly unhealthy and debauched,
而与此同时，普通的德国民众还在忍受战时的配给制
while ordinary Germans suffered wartime rationing.
但这些就能说明他是同性恋吗
But does any of this mean that he was gay?
不，并不能
No, it doesn't.
事实上，一些作家指出
In fact, some authors have noted
戈林主要是在私底下表现出——
that Göring exhibited mostly in private,
因为他的衣服、妆容和珠宝——
due to his clothes, make-up, and jewellery,
一种异装癖的倾向
a tendency towards transvestism,
也就是一个男人通过穿女装来获得性快感
that is, a man who derives sexual pleasure from dressing in female clothing.
但我和其他许多人，对此持保留意见
I, and many others, would dispute this.
如果你仔细看看目击者们
If you look closely at what witnesses said
对戈林私下着装品味的描述
of Göring's sartorial tastes in private,
什么和服啊，托加长袍啊之类的
the kimonos, togas, etc.,
他根本就没把自己打扮成女人
he wasn't dressing as a woman at all,
尽管他确实用了些娘娘腔的化妆品和珠宝
despite the effeminate use of make-up and jewellery.
实际上，他是在把自己打扮成一个非常光鲜亮丽又带点儿阴柔气质的男人
He was, in fact, dressing as a very glamorous and slightly effeminate man.
我的意思是
What I mean is,
戈林的制服和服装
Göring's uniforms and clothing
都是男式的，但又完全用力过猛
were male, but completely over the top,
搞得跟漫画人物似的
to the point of becoming caricature,
一只穿着舞台戏服的开屏孔雀
a peacock dressed almost in stage costumes.
没有任何流言说戈林在性方面喜欢男人
No rumours exist that Göring enjoyed male company in a sexual way,
也没有任何心怀不满的前男友在他死后这八十年里冒出来爆料说
nor any disgruntled former boyfriends have emerged in the past eight decades since his death,
他是个同性恋或者双性恋
alleging that he was a homosexual or bisexual.
但是有一个词可以形容戈林的这种癖好
But there is a name for Göring's predilection.
这个词来自心理学，对我来说也是个新知识
It is found in psychology, and it's a new one on me.
我以前从没听说过
I'd never heard of it before.
赫尔曼·戈林
Hermann Göring was,
据一些专家说
according to some experts,
是个“同性着装癖”者
a homo-vestite.
那么，啥是同性着装癖
So what is homo-vestism?
这是一种特别的性偏好，偏好同性别的服装
It is a particular sexual preference for same-sex clothing,
而不是异性服装，也就是异装癖
as opposed to cross-dressing.
一个有同性着装癖的人
One who identifies as a homo-vestite
会从服装和行为中获得性快感
would derive sexual pleasure from clothing and behaviour
而这些服装和行为，被认为是符合自己性别的常规操作
that is considered normative to their own gender.
但重点是
But importantly,
穿着自己性别的衣服，要么是强迫性地穿
the wearing of the clothes of one's own gender, either obsessively,
比如说一个男人，只穿西装打领带，每天都这么穿，雷打不动
such as a man who only wears a tie and a suit all the time, every day.
要么就像戈林这样，搞得特别夸张
Or is it the case of Göring with exaggeration?
那些滑稽歌剧般的制服
The comic opera uniforms,
奇怪的狩猎装
the strange hunting outfits,
罗马式长袍、和服、化妆，过多的奖章、配饰和珠宝
the Roman dress and kimonos and make-up, the excessive medals, accoutrements, and jewellery.
“同性着装癖”这个词，最早是由希腊精神分析学家乔治·扎维齐亚诺斯创造的
Homo-vestism was first coined by Greek psychoanalyst George Zavitsanos.
我倒是很想听听那些看了这个节目的精神病学家或者心理学家的看法
I'd be interested to hear from any psychiatrists or psychologists who have seen this programme,
你们觉得“同性着装癖”这个诊断能不能用在赫尔曼·戈林身上？
and whether you think homo-vestism could be applied to Hermann Göring.
再重申一遍，从现有证据来看
From the available evidence, once again,
戈林显然不是同性恋
Göring apparently wasn't homosexual,
也不是双性恋
nor was he bisexual,
甚至也不是异装癖
nor even a transvestite,
但很明显，他跟他身边的人非常不一样
but clearly he was very different from those around him,
而“同性着装癖”这个理论，可以说是八九不离十了
and homo-vestism seems to explain his dress and behaviour fairly accurately.
感谢收看
Many thanks for watching.
请关注并分享
Please subscribe and share,
也欢迎访问我的有声书频道
and also visit my audiobook channel,
马克·费尔顿的战争故事
War Stories with Mark Felton.
您也可以通过PayPal和Patreon支持我的两个频道
You can also help to support both of my channels at PayPal and Patreon.
链接在简介
Details in the description box below.